Charlie Scott

charliejscott@outlook.com | linkedin.com/in/charliejscott | github.com/cscott20

SUMMARY

Hello! My name is Charlie and I'm an fullstack software engineer focused on building beautiful and high traffic products. At Echo AI, I have experience building with Python / Django for backend, Javascript / React for frontend, and CSS for styling. I also have experience building in Java during my time at Epsilon. On a team, I'm a leader who pushes for customer-first design and seamless user experiences. I also enjoy coordinating team wide events, and playing my part in building a fun and productive team culture that I'm proud to be a part of.

EXPERIENCE

Echo AI

June 2021–Present

Fullstack Software Engineer | New York, NY

Frontend Development

- Experience with JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind.
- Focus on customer-first design, prioritizing a seamless user experience.
- Designing and implementing new, reusable, high-traffic customer-facing components daily.
- Developing reusable heatmap grid components, tables, charts, and other data visualization tools.
- Team design expert for complicated new UI/UX features.

Backend Development

- · Implementing continuous improvement plan to incrementally improve product performance & anticipate scaling.
- Introducing new logic to improve performance and scalability, such as optimizing database queries and pagination techniques.
- Designing reusable database schemas and API endpoints to support ongoing projects.
- Developing algorithms to intelligently select LLM analysis in need of human feedback.

Leadership & Ownership

- Owner and lead developer of Analytics and Performance platforms, generating over \$1m in revenue in <200 days.
- Leading team retrospectives, identifying team goals, and hosting lunch and learn series.
- Onboarding and mentoring new engineers. Leading small teams towards product and feature roadmap goals.
- · Volunteer culture ambassador, leading recurring team-building events including game days, team bonding, etc.
- Directly working with customer-facing teams, and creating roadmaps to implement feature requests over time.
- Writing technical documentation, leading design discussions, and tech debt/bug bashes.

Epsilon Sept 2020–June 2021

Fullstack Software Engineer | San Francisco, CA

Frontend Development

• Designed and deployed new employee-facing website to allow for safe database interactions.

Backend Development

- · Automated labor-intensive developer tasks related to monitoring of company cloud platform performance.
- Proactively maintained cloud infrastructure to ensure smooth and efficient operations.

Cigna June 2019–Aug 2019

Intern | Santa Monica, CA

Backend Development

- Independently contacted and worked with product managers to understand business needs, leading to the initiation of a new project to automate online data collection previously done manually.
- Integrated this new application with existing manual data collection pipelines to ease transition.
- Developed tools to speed existing process of manual data collection efforts by upwards of 30% per employee.

EDUCATION

BS Mathematics, Computer Science

Aug~2017--June~2020

California Polytechnic University, SLO

• Graduated early with honors, including Dean's List recognition and an Academic Excellence Award of Honor. Received the Department of Mathematics Glassco Scholarship for academic excellence.